<chapter id="torrent">
  <title>Torrent</title>

<section id="state"><title>State</title>

<section id="closed"><title>Closed</title>

<para>
This is the initial state of a download. When switching to this mode,
all tracker requests are closed and the bitfield of completed chunks
is cleared. File paths can only be changed in this state. Functions
for getting information on bitfields, chunk count and various others
will return size 0 in this state. (TODO: Check which)
</para>

<para>
<blockquote>
<programlisting>
torrent::Download::is_open() == false;
torrent::Download::is_active() == false;
torrent::Download::is_tracker_busy() == false;
</programlisting>
</blockquote>
</para>

</section>

<section id="open"> <title>Open</title>

<para>
This is the state after a successfull call to
torrent::Download::open(). This function throws torrent::local_error
if the download could not be opened. All files in the download have
been created and are open. The initial hash check must be done to get
a valid bitfield of completed chunks.
</para>

<para>
<blockquote>
<programlisting>
torrent::Download::is_open() == true;
torrent::Download::is_active() == false;
</programlisting>
</blockquote>
</para>

</section>

<section id="active"> <title>Active</title>

<para>
A download is active after calling torrent::Download::start(). Only
downloads that are in an open state and has a valid bitfield of
completed chunks can be activated.
</para>

<para>
<blockquote>
<programlisting>
torrent::Download::is_open() == true;
torrent::Download::is_active() == true;
torrent::Download::is_hash_checked() == true;
</programlisting>
</blockquote>
</para>

<para>
A tracker request will be made when torrent::Download::stop() is
called on an active download. It is not required to wait for the
tracker request to finish before calling torrent::Download::close(),
but it is recommened so the tracker knows this client is not available.
</para>

</section>
</section>


<section id="file-paths">
<title>File Paths</title>

<para>
The paths of files in a Download consists of two parts, the
root directory and the paths of each file. The file paths are read
from the torrent file and the files usually reside in the root
directory. The root directory is by default "./" for single file
torrents and "./[torrent_name]/" for multi-file torrents.
</para>


<para>
<blockquote>
<programlisting>
// Get and set the root directory.
std::string    torrent::Download::get_root_dir();
void           torrent::Download::set_root_dir(const std::string& dir);

// Get the torrent::Entry class for each file in the download.
torrent::Entry torrent::Download::get_entry(uint32_t index);
uint32_t       torrent::Download::get_entry_size();

typedef std::list&lt;std::string> torrent::Entry::Path;

// Get and set the file path.
std::string    torrent::Entry::get_path();
const Path&    torrent::Entry::get_path_list();

void           torrent::Entry::set_path_list(const Path& l);
</programlisting>
</blockquote>
</para>


<para>
The modifications can only be done while the download is in a
closed state. Modifying the file paths will not change the "info hash"
part of the bencode'd torrent associated with the download. (TODO:
When exporting, save root directory and file paths to another section
of the torrent)
</para>

</section>


